{"description":"A set of questions to test the software with","name":"Pilot (Sep 13)","version":1,"questions":[{"question":"1. Pilots shall not exchange seats during flight if only two pilots are aboard the airplane.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 4-2, Warning","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"2. Verbal coordination between applicable crewmembers will be required when:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 4-2","responses":["Control of the airplane is transferred between pilot and copilot or when an autopilot mode or axis is engaged or disengaged.","Repositioning fuel panel valves and switches or when an electrical source is changed.","A crewmember leaves position or leaves interphone or goes on or off oxygen.","Any of the above."]},{"question":"3. Normal hydraulic pressure range is ____ to ____ psi.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 5-7","responses":["1000; 3000","2400; 3050","1500; 2800","1971; 2469"]},{"question":"4. Maximum EGT during engine start is _____*C.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 5-3","responses":["870","905","725","930"]},{"question":"5. EGT between ________is limited to 5 minutes duration. EGT between _____________ \u2212 Retard the throttle to bring EGT within limits. Operation is allowed until the next landing. If the EGT exceeds _______ \u2212 shut engine down using the ENGINE FIRE\/FAILURE DURING FLIGHT checklist.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 5-8","responses":["725*C - 870*C; 871*C - 905*C; 906*C","870*C - 905*C; 906*C - 930*C; 930*C","725*C - 870*C; 906*C - 930*C; 930*C","The green arc"]},{"question":"6. Normal oil pressure limits are _______ psi. Oil pressure fluctuations of not more than ___ psi total are allowable, as long as fluctuations remain within normal limits.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 5-3","responses":["5 - 100; 5","11 - 92; 10","20 - 85; 15","30 - 60; 20"]},{"question":"7. Moderate to severe airplane buffeting can occur with simultaneous use of speed brakes and flaps. This buffeting can result in damage or loss of airplane surfaces.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 5-13","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"8. Because of possible damage due to sonic airflow at certain angles of attack, do not extend flaps above _____ feet pressure altitude.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 5-13","responses":["20000","15000","10,000","5,000"]},{"question":"9. The takeoff and emergency procedures portion will be reviewed either just prior to _____","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-2","responses":["Stepping to Aircraft","Engine Start","Takeoff","B or C"]},{"question":"10. Based on ________________________________, the aircraft commander may elect single pilot preflight operations where one pilot proceeds to the aircraft with the boom operator to perform the exterior safety check and begin the interior preflight checks, while the other pilot accomplishes additional duties (obtaining weather brief, etc.).","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-2","responses":["Operational Need","Mission Requirements","Personal Preference","A or B"]},{"question":"11. All crewmembers will inform the pilot when checking off and\/or on interphone and will be on interphone during:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 4-3","responses":["All ground operations (including engine starts) except when accomplishing crew duties that preclude use of interphone.","Formation flying, rendezvous and air refueling.","Flight under weather conditions and all takeoffs and landings","All of the above."]},{"question":"12. Because of the magnitude of interrelated aerodynamic effects, flying two airplanes in close vertical proximity is _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 5-18","responses":["Routine","Safe","Not safe","Not recommended"]},{"question":"13. Speed brakes are NOT used during approach and landing flare.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 6-18","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"14. All snow and ice accumulations of any significant degree must be removed from the airplane surfaces prior to takeoff.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 7-14","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"15. If the ___________ is not down and in the detent, ensure that the _____________ is installed. Notify the aircraft commander and maintenance personnel immediately. No further preflight actions will be accomplished until maintenance personnel correct the situation and confirm that the aircraft is in preflight configuration.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-7, Caution","responses":["Flap Handle; Override Crank","Crew Entry Chute Grill; Crew Entry Ladder","Landing Gear Lever; nose gear ground downlock and release handle","Speed Brake Lever; Flight Control Snubbers"]},{"question":"16. The pilot will ensure that no personnel are standing near ____________ when pressurizing the left hydraulic system. Sudden closing of these doors could cause serious injury to personnel who may be in the path of the doors.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-15, Warning","responses":["Cargo Door","Wheel Well Doors","Main Entry Door","APU Exhaust Doors"]},{"question":"18. Possible causes of a _____________ are engaging the pilot\u2019s interphone (on the yoke or the tiller), pressing the pilot\u2019s FD ANN TEST button, a cold hydraulic system, the lowflow capability of the auxiliary hydraulic pump, and\/or the use of other hydraulicallyactuated systems during the EFAS test; in this case, the EFAS self-test is _____________ indicating a system failure.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-22, Note","responses":["Failed EFAS test; correctly","Failed EFAS test; incorrectly","Failed SYD test; not applicable and","Failed SYD test; correctly"]},{"question":"19. Speed Brake Warning horn sounds when lever is pulled back more than __ degrees out of the full forward position.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-31","responses":["5","6","2","4"]},{"question":"20. Proper adjustment of the __________ is especially critical for takeoff, approach, and landing where full deflection of control surfaces may be required for safe operation of the airplane. To prevent inadvertent movement of the seat, ensure that the ______________ is in the down and latched position.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-42, Warning","responses":["Seat Belts and Shoulder Harnesses; seat vertical adjustment lever","Seat and Rudder Pedals; seat vertical adjustment lever","Seat and Rudder Pedals; seat horizontal adjustment lever","Seat Belts and Shoulder Harnesses; seat horizontal adjustment lever"]},{"question":"21. If an APU with an operable generator is not available, and external power is not used, the start can be made on battery power only. During this procedure, all engine ___________ gages are inoperative until a generator is on the line and 28V AC power is available.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-62, Notes","responses":["Oil Pressure and Fuel Flow","N1 and N2","Oil Low Pressure Lights and EGT","Instrument"]},{"question":"22. Copilot checks for initial fuel flow peak of ___ pph (before ignition) and approximately ___ pph after ignition. If fuel flow exceeds ___ pph before lightoff, a hot start can occur.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-63, Note","responses":["100; 1000; 100","300-680; 900; 680","725; 870; 930","Within the Green Arc"]},{"question":"23. For temperatures _________, failure to set the engine start switch to IGNITION may result in engine flameout when the throttles are retarded during taxi operations.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-64, Note","responses":["Colder than normal","At and below 10C (50F)","At and below 4C (40F)","At and below 0C (32F)"]},{"question":"24. Items 18. thru 29. of the Starting Engines and Before Taxi checklist may be accomplished while waiting for the ground crew report.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-65, Note","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"25. Minimum taxiway width is _____ feet.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Paragraph 5.18.1","responses":["147","74","75","100"]},{"question":"26. Do not taxi or tow an aircraft within _____ feet of obstructions without wing walkers monitoring the clearance between the aircraft and the obstruction. Do not taxi aircraft closer than _____ feet to any obstruction.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFI 11-218 AMC SUP, Paragraphs 1.22.2., 1.22.3","responses":["43763","25, 10","10, 10","25, 25"]},{"question":"27. When taxi clearance is doubtful, use _____ wing walkers.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Paragraph 5.19.2","responses":["One or more","Two or more","Three or more","Four or more"]},{"question":"28. Make every effort to minimize the potential for engine FOD. Crews should:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Paragraph 5.19.3 and 5.19.3.1.1","responses":["Carefully review airfield layout paying particular attention to taxi routes, turn requirements, and areas for potential FOD.","Minimize power settings during all taxi operations.","Where possible, avoid taxi operations that position an engine over an unprepared or un-swept surface. If unavoidable, leave the engine in idle (to the maximum extent possible) until the engine is over an improved surface.","All of the Above"]},{"question":"29. What is the minimum taxi spacing during formation:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Paragraph 18.6.3","responses":["Safe interval","150 feet","75 feet","50 feet"]},{"question":"30. During night taxi operations, marshallers will have ______________ in each hand.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Paragraph 5.19.2","responses":["A Whistle","A Wand","An Illuminated Wand","Gloves"]},{"question":"31. Air Force pilots may passively participate in LAHSO (land or take-off when another aircraft has been given a LAHSO clearance). PIC is the final authority whether to takeoff, land or continue a touch-and-go when a merging aircraft has received a LAHSO clearance.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFI 11-202 Vol 3, Paragraph 5.11.5.1","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"33. You are approaching another aircraft on the ground head-on. What should you do?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFI 11-218 AMC SUP, Paragraph 1.20.1.1","responses":["Keep moving in the direction intended. You have the right-of-way and the other aircraft will move.","Alter course to the left to remain well clear, or stop.","Alter the course to the right to remain well clear, or stop.","Execute a 180 degree turn and return to parking."]},{"question":"34. When taxi clearance is doubtful and wing walkers are not available, _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Paragraph 5.19.2","responses":["continue to follow marshaling instructions as the marshaller is trained not to taxi aircraft into obstacles","if at a Navy\/Marine airfield, continue to taxi since taxi obstacle clearances at these fields are waived.","deplane one or more crewmembers to maintain obstruction clearance and provide marshalling using AFI 11-218 signals","all of the above."]},{"question":"35. In those situations where runway\/taxi conditions or performance considerations are such that safety could be compromised,","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-74, Caution","responses":["A static takeoff should be made.","A rolling or static\/rolling takeoff should be made","Extreme care should be given to calculating takeoff data","B and C"]},{"question":"36. For a takeoff, approach or landing with fuel in any main tank below ______ pounds, open all tank to engine manifold valves. Open the line valve for all takeoffs when gross weight is greater than _______ pounds. Ensure line valve is closed for all takeoffs when gross weight is at or below _______ pounds.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-75, Step 3 and Warning","responses":["Full; 322,500; 5,900","5,000; 180,000; 8,800","10,500; 200,000; 200,000","10,500; 180,000; 235,000"]},{"question":"37. Exercise caution during throttle application to prevent asymmetrical thrust. Engine thrust should be stabilized at a minimum of ________ prior to advancing throttles to the takeoff thrust setting.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-74, Caution","responses":["20% N1","40% N1","50% N1","Ground Idle"]},{"question":"38. Uncommanded stabilizer trim input is a safety-of-flight issue. Terminate the mission (and in flight, land as soon as practicable) any time uncommanded stabilizer trim input is encountered.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-74, Warning","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"39. If any engine does not reach the charted N1 setting _____, the engine is not providing the required rated thrust, and the takeoff shall be aborted.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-77, Warning","responses":["Upon initial takeoff power setting","Prior to 90 knots","Before S1","Between 40 and 80 knots"]},{"question":"40. Illumination of the amber EGT caution light near or after S1 indicates that EGT may be approaching the takeoff limit. This indication is for crew awareness and does not indicate an engine operating limit has been exceeded. Continue normal operation and monitor EGT to prevent exceeding the takeoff EGT limit.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-77, Note","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"41. When _____ throttle is advanced near OPEN, the warning horn sounds if the speed brake lever is more than 2 degrees out of the full forward position, if the flap lever is at or near the 0, 40, or 50 degree detent, or the leading edge flaps are not fully extended.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-77","responses":["No. 1","No. 2","No. 3","No. 4"]},{"question":"42. Sudden reversal of rudder direction, at high rudder deflections, due to improper rudder application or abrupt release, can result in ____________.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-83","responses":["Failure of the rudder PCU","Failure of the rudder pressure controller","Over-G of the aircraft","Overstressing the vertical fin."]},{"question":"43. If stabilizer trim has moved from setting selected during the TAXI checklist, _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-74, Step 2","responses":["Abort the mission","Reset to original setting","Call maintenance","Immediately place the stabilizer trim switch to the CUT-OFF position and manually trim throughout departure."]},{"question":"44. When experiencing a loss shear on takeoff, anticipate a loss in indicated airspeed and altitude. This situation is potentially dangerous if the airplane is close to the ground. If this loss is expected to be ___ knots or more, the takeoff shall be delayed, if possible, until more favorable conditions exist.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 7-7","responses":["10","15","20","25"]},{"question":"45. When the airplane is definitely airborne and a positive rate of climb is established (vertical velocity pointer above zero), retract the landing gear.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-84","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"46. Follow Dash One procedures for the climb mode selected until reaching _____ or obstacle clearance height, whichever is higher.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-84","responses":["Flap retraction height","Departure end of runway","2000 feet above the runway","Level off altitude"]},{"question":"47. Leave ignition on if engine anti-ice is on. If anti-ice is not required, turn starter switches off _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-88, Step 4","responses":["once climb thrust is established","upon reaching 2000 feet","Both A and B","5 minutes after established at cruise altitude"]},{"question":"48. Do not climb at a speed more than the recommended three engine climbout speed.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-84, Warning","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"49. Maneuvering at speeds below three engine climbout speed plus ___ knots is not recommended. A bank angle of 30 degrees at climbout speed with flaps down could reduce climb capability by as much as ____fpm.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-84, Warning","responses":["10, 200","25, 300","35, 300","50, 400"]},{"question":"50. If airplane is to remain in closed traffic after takeoff, thrust will be adjusted to climb out at the same speed to be used on the downwind leg, and a rate of climb of approximately _____ feet per minute.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-84","responses":["500","1000","1500","2500"]},{"question":"51. If an engine failure occurs during climbout, continue to follow the command bars. With inoperative command bars, if an engine failure occurs during or immediately after takeoff, __________________________________; if an engine failure occurs after attaining three engine climbout speed, do not reduce airspeed but continue to climb at the speed attained at the point of engine failure.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-85, Warning","responses":["Increase thrust to accelerate to enroute climb speed","Climb at Vco + 10","Climb at recommended three-engine climbout speed","Land immediately"]},{"question":"52. Flap retraction in a turn is not recommended. Retracting flaps from 20 degrees to 0 reduces available lateral (outboard ailerons) control and increases initial buffet speed considerably and rapidly as the trailing edge and leading edge flaps retract.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-87","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"53. After setting climb thrust, no further throttle adjustment should be necessary during climb if the power management control (PMC) system is NOT operating.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-87","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"54. A departure alternate is required if weather is below landing minimums for the lowest suitable approach (at departure aerodrome). To qualify as a departure alternate, the airfield must be:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, para 6.19.2.1 and 6.19.2.2","responses":["Within 30 minutes flying time, the existing weather is equal to or better than the published approach minimums and forecast to remain so until 1 hour after takeoff.","Within one hour flying time, better than published mins for the lowest suitable approach (to include a circling approach) for until end AAR time.","Within two hours flying time, the existing weather is at least 500-1 above the lowest compatible published approach minimums, but not less than 600-2 (precision) or 800-2 (non-precision) and forecast to remain so for 1 hour after ETA at the alternate.","A or C"]},{"question":"55. Manual damping of dutch roll is to be accomplished only with ________________.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-37","responses":["Manual trim","Rudder","Lateral (aileron) control","Elevator"]},{"question":"56. For an unplanned thunderstorm penetration, use 280 KIAS or cruise Mach and do NOT change the ____________.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 7-5","responses":["Autopilot configuration","Stabilizer Trim setting","Route of flight","Steering solutions"]},{"question":"57. No HF transmissions are to be made from a tanker or receiver when a receiver is in contact or about to make contact and all HF equipment must be switched to STANDBY\/MONITOR when possible.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"ATP-56 Part 2, Chapter 5, para 503b","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"58. For all _____________ AARs, do not transmit on the HF radio when the receiver is within 1\/2 NM; this includes datalink.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"ATP-56 Part 5 Annex ZE-4-1, Warning","responses":["USAF","USN","USAF & USN","foreign aircraft"]},{"question":"59. Pilots must use extreme care in those cases when the speed brakes are required for deceleration. Ascertain that the receiver _____ prior to speed brake actuation.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-90D, Warning","responses":["will be established on track","is in the astern position","is in the contact position","will not overrun the tanker"]},{"question":"60. For airplanes equipped with standard speed booms: If airspeed must be increased above _____ KIAS\/.85 Mach, the pilot will notify the boom operator to stow the boom.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-90D, Caution","responses":["325","330","335","340"]},{"question":"61. During any boom air refueling which requires the indicated airspeed to be less than 220 KIAS, __________ for dry contacts, to preclude fuel siphoning from the forward body tank, causing unexpected CG changes.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-90R, Caution","responses":["place the A\/R manifold to engine manifold valve to CLOSE","minimize the number of requests","keep the center wing to forward body tank valve switches closed","keep the A\/R line valve closed"]},{"question":"62. When a receiver is in or near the contact position, the pilot __________________ at the first indication of autopilot malfunction, including an inadvertent disconnect, if accompanied by out-of-trim control forces.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-90F, Warning","responses":["will switch the autopilot attitude source from VG to INU-2","should initiate a breakaway","should start a gentle climb","will initiate a breakaway"]},{"question":"63. Air refueling for the receiver that required a controlled tension disconnect will be terminated except during fuel emergencies or when continuation of air refueling is dictated by operational necessity.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-79, Caution","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"64. Unless dictated otherwise by ATP-56 (Part 5, Annex ZE) or by mission requirements, tankers will establish the applicable contact air refueling airspeed before the receiver reaches ______. If the tanker is off airspeed by more than _____ knots, the receiver pilot will be informed prior to tanker airspeed changes.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-90D, Warning","responses":["1NM, 5","1NM, 10","Astern, 5","Astern, 10"]},{"question":"65. Following an inadvertent brute force disconnect, air refueling _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-79, Caution","responses":["may be continued if the tanker and receiver air refueling systems function normally","should be terminated","will be terminated","will be terminated except during fuel emergencies or when continuation of air"]},{"question":"66. The position approximately 50 ft behind and slightly below the tanker boom nozzle where the receiver stabilizes with zero rate of closure before being cleared to the contact position is called:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"ATP-56 Part 5, page ZE-4-2","responses":["Astern","Pre-Contact","Stabilized","Either A or B"]},{"question":"67. Tanker responsibilities during a Rendezvous Delta is (are) to:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"ATP-56 Part 2, Annex 1D, para 102D (c), page 1 D-4","responses":["Be at the base AAR altitude.","Enter the refueling holding orbit from any direction.","Attempt to arrive at least 15 min before the RVCT and, normally, establish a lefthand holding pattern using the RVCP as an anchor point.","All of the above"]},{"question":"68. When planning to conduct a Rendezvous G, a common track length equivalent to ____ min flying time should be planned to allow for tanker descent to RV FL\/altitude\/height, visual acquisition and timing corrections.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"ATP-56 Part 2, Annex 1G, para 102G(b), page 1 G-1","responses":["5","10","15","20"]},{"question":"69. Tankers will only refuel those aircraft listed in ATP-56 or specifically authorized by HQ AMC\/A3V. Receiver aircraft not previously certified for refueling operations (includes foreign variants of US-produced aircraft) must be certified for technical and operational compatibility in accordance with USAF regulations prior to refueling.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Paragraph 15.11.1","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"70. Unless otherwise directed, an altimeter setting of _____ is to be used for AAR operations at or above transition altitude, or when over water and operating in accordance with ICAO procedures. When not operating on standard pressure settings, tanker crews _____ to include the altimeter setting in the RV Initial Call.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"ATP-56, Part 2, Chapter 1, para 102a, page 1-1","responses":["QFE, are required","29.92, are required","29.92, are not required","QNH, are not required"]},{"question":"71. Tanker pilots will ensure the boom operator notifies receiver pilots when any axis of the autopilot is not used. If a tanker pilot or receiver pilot is required to fly autopilot-off for qualification training, the pilot flying the opposing aircraft will be qualified.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Paragraph 15.2.3","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"72. The tanker will note the receiver\u2019s distance when ________ through the turn back to the ARCP. This is the best time to determine if an overrun condition exists and the best time for visual sighting. Except for overtaking point parallel rendezvous, the distance to the receiver should be approximately 1\/3 of the turn range when _______ through the turn.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, page 2-90C","responses":["1\/3rd , halfway","Halfway, 1\/3","Halfway, halfway","Beginning, beginning"]},{"question":"73. Tanker aircrew will advise ATC of tanker and receiver end aerial refueling altitude requests at least five (5) minutes prior to AREX.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"JO 7610.4P, Para 10-1-6a.10","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"74. After experiencing two-way communications failure while conducting aerial refueling, tanker aircraft will discontinue AAR and continue flight by doing what?","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135 Vol 3, Para 15.3","responses":["Squawk code 7600 for at least two (2) minutes prior to exiting track or anchor","Exit the track or anchor at the highest altitude specified in the AAR clearance","Proceed in accordance with \"Procedures for Two-Way Radio Failure IFR-VFR\" setforth in the DoD Flight Information Handbook","All of the above"]},{"question":"75. Normally, tanker orbit patterns are located within a rectangle, 60nm long, 25nm wide with left turns. While established in and awaiting their receivers, tanker aircraft:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"JO 7610.4P, Paragraph 10-2-5, Note","responses":["Are automatically cleared down to the IP, if needed for rendezvous.","Must receive clearance from the box to the IP, if airspace is desired.","Can change direction of turn, if they wish.","Must notify ATC if shortening leg lengths."]},{"question":"76. The crew must closely monitor the airplane CG during reverse air refueling. The aft CG limit can be quickly exceeded in airplanes operating at _____ gross weights.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-44C, Warning","responses":["Light","Heavy","Medium","Maximum"]},{"question":"77. Routing and altitudes(s) of aircraft established on an approved ALTRV shall not be changed except in the interest of safety of flight or as outlined in Chapter 3 of JO 7610.4P.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"JO 7610.4P, Para 3-3-8","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"78. To avoid an automatic rejection of the logon request, the flight crew ensures that the flightspecific information entered into the aircraft system is the same as the corresponding details filed _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"GOLD Manual, Para 2.2.3.2.3","responses":["On the Form F","In the Aircrew Briefing Guide","By the Copilot","In the flight plan"]},{"question":"79. After obtaining and reading back the clearance, the pilot should monitor the forward estimate for oceanic entry, and if this changes by _____ minutes or more, the pilot must pass a revised estimate to ATC.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"North Atlantic MNPSA Operations Manual, Para 5.1.7","responses":["1","2","3","5"]},{"question":"80. Crews will use ___________________ for oceanic crossings.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135, Vol 3, Para 6.34.1","responses":["The in-flight guide","Only the MNPS Oceanic Checklist and the Oceanic Expanded Checklist","Locally generated oceanic checklists","AP1B"]},{"question":"81. If operating on an ALTRV and mission is to be delayed beyond the AVANA time, rescheduling the ALTRV,","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"JO 7610.4P, Para 3-4-4","responses":["Will normally be in 24-hour increments after the original schedule.","Is at the discretion of the mission commander","Can be in less than the time specified above, subject to CARF discretion and after approval from the affected ARTCC\/CERAP\/HCF.","A or C"]},{"question":"82. While flying the oceanic route, crews will maintain situational awareness to include positional awareness and accurate fuel readings. In order to assist with this, crews will:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135, Vol 3, Para 11.7.1","responses":["When approaching each waypoint on a Category I route, recheck coordinates for the next waypoints.","Approximately 10 minutes after passing each oceanic waypoint, record and plot the aircraft position and time on the chart, and ensure compliance with courses and ETA tolerances.","If a revised clearance is received, record and plot the new route of flight on the chart.","All of the above"]},{"question":"83. An ATSU cannot establish a CPDLC connection without first completing the AFN logon.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"GOLD Manual, Para 5.2.1.1","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"84. If a logon request has been initiated with incorrect aircraft identification and aircraft registration, the logon process will fail. The flight crew will need to _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"GOLD Manual, Para 5.2.1.2 Note","responses":["Call Command Post to verify aircraft registration.","Transmit AFN logon, then re-transmit with correct identification.","Omit AFN logon from checklist.","Correct the information and reinitiate the logon request."]},{"question":"85. Approximately _____ minutes after exiting CPDLC and\/or ADS-C service areas, the flight crew should ensure there are no active CPDLC or ADS-C connections.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"GOLD Manual, Para 5.2.5.2","responses":["15","30","40","45"]},{"question":"86. Experience has shown that many of the track-keeping errors in the NAT MNPS Airspace occur as a result of crews programming the navigation system(s) with incorrect waypoint data. These are referred to as Waypoint Insertion Errors. They frequently originate from:","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"North Atlantic MNPSA Operations Manual, Para 5.7.3","responses":["Failure to observe the principles of checking waypoints to be inserted in the navigation systems, against the ATC cleared route","Failure to load waypoint information carefully","Failure to cross-check on-board navigation systems","Any combination of the above"]},{"question":"87. Steep idle thrust approaches, or all approach angles and rates of descent requiring large changes in pitch attitude during the landing flare, will be avoided.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-98, Warning","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"88. For approach purposes, the KC-135R is considered a Category __ airplane. In those cases where the speed for a circling approach exceeds 166 knots, Category __ minima will be applied.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-94, Note","responses":["C, D","D, E","D, D","C, C"]},{"question":"89. A speed brake lever position of less than ___ degrees is not recommended, due to a tendency to over-control at these settings.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-91, Note","responses":["20","30","40","50"]},{"question":"90. For all FMS approaches, at 2 NM prior to the final approach fix ensure system is in the __________ mode (as indicated by the blinking _____________ CDU annunciation), or discontinue the approach.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-94, Note","responses":["Terminal, <>","Enroute, <>","Approach, <>","Message <>"]},{"question":"91. If multiple instrument approach patterns are flown in the clean configuration, maintain a minimum of ___________ KIAS until crossing the initial approach fix or turning base leg if receiving radar vectors.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-94, Note","responses":["VREF","VREF + 25","VREF + 50","VREF +70"]},{"question":"92. Unless fuel consumption is a factor, hold at ________ for all gross weights up to 170,000 pounds. At gross weights above 170,000 pounds, use _______________________ knots as holding speed.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-91","responses":["220 KIAS, best endurance plus 10","200 KIAS, 220 KIAS","VREF +50, VREF +25","220 KIAS, best range plus 10"]},{"question":"93. Occupants of the pilot and copilot seats may remove the shoulder harness during cruise flight, but shall fasten them prior to _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-92, Note","responses":["Air refueling rendezvous","Descent for landing","A and B","None of the above"]},{"question":"94. As a minimum, the pilot flying the approach will brief the crew on the planned descent rate, DH\/MDA\/VDP, missed approach procedures and assign crew responsibilities for backing up the pilot flying the airplane _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-92, Item 2","responses":["During the full stop landing","If windshear is encountered along the final approach course","While accomplishing a touch and go landing","If an unplanned go-around occurs"]},{"question":"95. From 500\u2019 AGL to the runway, the PF will execute a go-around\/missed approach when which of the following parameters are exceeded.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"AFI 11-2KC-135, Vol 3, Para 5.12.1.2 - 5.12.1.3.1.3","responses":["Airspeed: +10\/-5 knots from target","Bank Angle: +\/- 15 degrees","Rate of Descent: +\/- 300 FPM from target","Any of the above"]},{"question":"96. During the descent checklist, an accurate check of the electric and hydraulic systems consists of the pilot checking switches and pressure in the left, right, reserve brake and powered rudder systems while the copilot checks electrical power system indicators and hydraulic quantities.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-93","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"97. When landing with less than full flaps, avoid excessive flare with resultant floating in an attempt for a smooth landing. Make a normal flare and touchdown at _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-99, Warning","responses":["Threshold speed minus 10 knots","Threshold speed minus 5 knots","Vapp for the applicable flap setting","VREF"]},{"question":"98. Application of _______ brakes during landing ground roll may override the _______ antiskid brake system and lock the airplane brakes resulting in possible blown tires or reverted rubber hydroplaning.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-99, Caution","responses":["Pilot, Co-Pilot","Pilot, Pilot","Co-Pilot, Pilot","Co-Pilot, Co-Pilot"]},{"question":"99. Engine acceleration from ground idle to touch and go target thrust may require up to 20 seconds. Attempting a go-around after the engines have decelerated to ground idle results in an extended ground run. Consider aborting the takeoff if the engines go to ground idle.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-107, Warning","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"100. Touchdown with a crab angle and with wings level may result in a rapid rising of the _________wing and may cause the ______engine nacelles to drag on the runway.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-99, Caution","responses":["Upwind, Upwind","Downwind, Downwind","Downwind, Upwind","Upwind, Downwind"]},{"question":"101. Do not allow the bank angle at touchdown (4 to 6 degrees pitch attitude) to exceed _____ degrees due to possibility of dragging an outboard engine nacelle.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-99, Caution","responses":["4","6","8","9"]},{"question":"102. During landing ground roll, do not allow airplane to bank beyond ____ degrees due to possibility of dragging an engine nacelle.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-99, Caution","responses":["4","6","8","9"]},{"question":"103. Prior to initiating turns, visually check for other traffic. The first turn should not be initiated until _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-100, Warning","responses":["Reaching minimum traffic pattern (maneuver) speed","A safe altitude","Passing the end of the runway","All of the above"]},{"question":"104. Remove crab _______________, maintaining a slight wing low attitude into the wind, as necessary to counteract drift.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-99","responses":["Over the threshold","Prior to touchdown","When pulling power","Prior to the threshold"]},{"question":"105. N1 settings, pattern, approach, and reference speeds will be recomputed when: (1) Gross weight changes >\/= ________ pounds (2) Temperature changes >\/= ___ (5F) (3) Pressure altitude changes >\/= ___ feet (4) Airplane configuration changes (5) Changes in wind conditions require an adjustment to the charted speeds","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-104, Note","responses":["5,000; 5C; 500 feet","10,000; 3C; 250 feet","10,000; 3C; 500 feet","5,000; 2C; 500 feet"]},{"question":"106. During a go-around, the minimum airspeed for retracting flaps to ___ degrees is flaps 50 Vth speed.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-106, Step D","responses":["50","40","30","20"]},{"question":"107. _____ Due to the lack of surge protection features, reverse refueling is prohibited.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-189, Warning","responses":["[ARR E]","[ARR B]","[ARR C]","[ARR G]"]},{"question":"108. Except in an emergency, do not engage or disengage the ____________ while in the contact position, as an unscheduled attitude change can occur about the vertical\/longitudinal axes.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 8-7, Warning","responses":["EFAS","Stabilizer trim brake","Series yaw damper","Antiskid"]},{"question":"109. When transferring fuel, only ____ A\/R pump(s) shall be operated at a time. This precludes the possibility of over-pressurizing a fuel tank if a fuel level control valve fails in the open position.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-80, Warning","responses":["4","3","2","1"]},{"question":"110. Monitor the fuel quantity gauges to avoid exceeding airplane _______ limits. Maintain symmetrical fuel quantities in the wing tanks to prevent lateral unbalance.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-80, Warning","responses":["CG","Structural","Maneuvering","Fuel Tank"]},{"question":"111. [Manual Boom Latching] The receiver pilot must initiate all disconnects before _____________________.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-80B, Caution","responses":["fatigue sets in","over pressurizing the ARR manifold","exceeding any of the limits","called by the boom operator"]},{"question":"112. The ____________ valve will be CLOSED before operation of the air refueling pumps because fuel pressure surges could cause rupture of the ___ manifold in the cockpit area.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 8-6, Warning","responses":["tank to engine manifold; tank to engine manifold","single point refueling; single point refueling","main ARR\/IFR; ARR","tank to engine manifold; main IFR"]},{"question":"113. A controlled tension brute force disconnect will be accomplished only _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-42, Caution","responses":["by a qualified instructor boom","as a last resort, after all other normal and emergency methods of disconnect have failed","when agreed upon by both the receiver and tanker","on [ARR E] configured jets"]},{"question":"114. The receiver pilot should use caution not to overrun the tanker. If overrunning does occur, under no conditions should a turn, either right or left, be made until _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-18A, Warning","responses":["a breakaway has been completed","speed brakes are deployed","the tanker is visual","throttles are advanced"]},{"question":"115. Approaching boom limits at relatively high velocity can cause _________ due to binding action of the boom nozzle.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 8-4, Caution","responses":["operating limits to be exceeded prior to disconnect","negative contact indication","structural damage as a result of an inability to disconnect","a pressure disconnect"]},{"question":"116. The receiver will stabilize in the astern position with a _____ rate of closure. If the receiver fails to attain a stabilized position, or it becomes apparent that a closure overrun will occur, a breakaway will be initiated. Failure to initiate a breakaway under closure overrun conditions can result in a mid-air collision.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 8-3, Warning","responses":["slight","zero","negative","slow"]},{"question":"117. If the receiver director lights fail to illuminate when contact is established, the ______ will inform the _______ if refueling operations are to be continued. If refueling is continued, verbal corrections from the boom operator may be requested.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 2-90H & 8-3, Caution","responses":["receiver copilot; tanker copilot","receiver pilot; tanker pilot","receiver pilot; boom operator","boom operator; receiver pilot"]},{"question":"118. The boom operator is unable to release the boom toggles during manual boom latching.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":0,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 3-80B, Caution","responses":["TRUE","FALSE"]},{"question":"119. One of the greatest potential hazards during air refueling is __________. On becoming fatigued or if for any reason large oscillations develop which require increasing amounts of control displacement, break contact and _________ the airplane in the astern position for a few minutes.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":1,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 8-4","responses":["Explosive vapors, ventilate","Fatigue, let the other pilot fly","flameout of engines, look around","rupture of the ARR manifold in the cockpit area"]},{"question":"120. Attempts to effect a contact during loss of any air refueling lighting that results in less than desired illumination will be at the discretion of the _____.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":2,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 8-3, Caution","responses":["receiver pilot","tanker pilot","boom operator","instructor pilot"]},{"question":"121. If the receiver is more than ___ in trail with the tanker, airspeed may be increased to ___ KIAS for closure. The normal speed schedule will be resumed at 3 NM in trail.","type":"multiple_choice","correct_response":3,"ref":"T.O. 1C-135(K)R(II)-1, Page 8-2, Note","responses":["3NM; 350","3NM; 330","4NM; 350","4NM; 330"]}]}
